<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Web Design Blog</title>
		<description>Stylish Jekyll Theme</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>How Much Does A Website Cost?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m sure to ruffle the feathers of a ton of designers, developers, and agencies at the mention of discussing price out in the open. I’m sure to stir the pot of opinions that could very well be their own version of truth. Ultimately I’m certain to shock the Clarks off of the business owner looking to “re-do” their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this friction and emotion for the sake of attempting to add clarity to a very commonly asked question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much should a website cost?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is simple: A lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could end at that… but come on, who are we kidding? You found this link in the hopes of seeing some sort of breakdown with actual real life prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s do this…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before a price-tag can be pinned to a product, consideration needs to be given to the production value. With website creation this is best served up in the increment of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours = Dollars&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the golden rule web designers and developers live by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, there are turn-key solutions and ready to purchase themes that can be literally picked from the shelf, slapped on your domain, dressed up with a custom color scheme, and branded with your company logo all for the one time cost of $29.99. This path is the right route to take for some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For others who need a more customizable approach to their on-line presence, the path ahead is mapped out. Proceed with enthusiasm and a willingness to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, the cost of a website is directly correlated to the number of hours it takes to create it. The downside to this approach, no two projects are exactly the same, making it a little tricky on the initial estimate. For the sake of arriving to a base price model I have listed the basic production stages of most website projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research and Planning (3 hours +)
Design (14 hours)
Front-end development (11 hours)
Back-end development (5 hours)
Content entry with 4 sub pages (5 hours)
Site Testing (2 hours)
Go-live (2 hours)
Hours for a basic site = 42 hours
Project Management Time = additional 20% of total time (8.4)
TOTAL HOURS = 50.4
As you can see, a very basic website, 4–5 pages, takes at the minimum 50 hours to complete. This leads us to the question of value. How much is that web design &amp;amp; development hour worth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of factors can attribute to an hourly rate, but the wisdom grounded in getting what you pay for often holds the most weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A designer or agency of great quality and high demand is going to expect to be paid what they are worth. A freelance designer just starting out may tread lightly until he or she feels worthy of charging a more standard rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way you can expect to see hourly rates as low as $50 an hour to as high as $150 an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our above tally of a 50 hour site that translates to paying anywhere between:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$2520 to as high as $7560 for a basic website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do your research, ask good questions, and set your expectations in line with your budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you cut corners on price, rest assured that corners are being cut on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 11:23:16 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/web/design/marketing/2018/09/24/how-much-does-a-website-cost.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/web/design/marketing/2018/09/24/how-much-does-a-website-cost.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>5 Tips For Dads Working From Home</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I run up the stairs, I run down the stairs, I run up the stairs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really beginning to 2nd guess our decision to purchase this two story fixer-upper. At the very least I am heavily considering moving the baby’s room to the middle of the living room… perhaps to the middle of the garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my children. Fatherhood has forced a posture of servant-hood inescapable and void of choice. These two-story castle princesses give commands, I respond. Mostly in love, some days in fear (our baby is trying to kill me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working while serving these lovely ladies requires a lot of planning and a little bit of self-defense. I’ve come up with a list that helps me get all of us through the day, still alive and if all goes well, still loving one another…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Your 1st priority is yourself. If you are not OK, you are not going to be able to be the best you can be for your family or your work. Also, babies and toddlers sense weakness like blood hounds and will strike at the 1st sign of vulnerability. Make sure you are getting enough sleep at night. Give yourself time in the morning before everyone wakes for a little “me” time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Silence is NOT golden. If you cannot see your children, hmm… not the end of the world. If you cannot hear your children… CODE RED! Silence is bad and usually means $h!% has hit the fan. Literally… poop is currently being spread on the walls of the hallway. Gracefully mute your conference call and run as fast as you can towards the silence. Be sure not to slip in the $h!%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) Your children are people. Treat them as such. There is no substitution for spending time with your kids. While you obviously have projects and tasks and emails in need of your attention be sure to schedule time for playing. Even if it is just for 10 minutes at a time. Those moments will go a long way towards communicating to your children their value and will, with all hope, spare them the desire to pursue a career in reality TV. Dad’s, don’t raise reality TV stars!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) Feed your kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.) Have grace. The quickest path towards destruction is you losing your cool. So what? Your 3 year old just flipped out, knocked the phone out of your hand disconnecting the call with a client, while screaming what sounded like an obscenity, all because you whispered to her she could not have cake right now. You are not a failure. You are a parent. Remain calm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember she is just a kid and the withholding of cake is a very valid reason for anyone to flip out. You kind of had it coming.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 11:23:16 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/web/design/marketing/remote-work/2018/09/24/5-tips-for-dads-working-from-home.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/web/design/marketing/remote-work/2018/09/24/5-tips-for-dads-working-from-home.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
