<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Web Design Blog</title>
		<description>Stylish Jekyll Theme</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>How Much Does A Website Cost?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m sure to ruffle the feathers of a ton of designers, developers, and agencies at the mention of discussing price out in the open. I’m sure to stir the pot of opinions that could very well be their own version of truth. Ultimately I’m certain to shock the Clarks off of the business owner looking to “re-do” their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this friction and emotion for the sake of attempting to add clarity to a very commonly asked question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much should a website cost?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is simple: A lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could end at that… but come on, who are we kidding? You found this link in the hopes of seeing some sort of breakdown with actual real life prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s do this…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before a price-tag can be pinned to a product, consideration needs to be given to the production value. With website creation this is best served up in the increment of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours = Dollars&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the golden rule web designers and developers live by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, there are turn-key solutions and ready to purchase themes that can be literally picked from the shelf, slapped on your domain, dressed up with a custom color scheme, and branded with your company logo all for the one time cost of $29.99. This path is the right route to take for some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For others who need a more customizable approach to their on-line presence, the path ahead is mapped out. Proceed with enthusiasm and a willingness to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, the cost of a website is directly correlated to the number of hours it takes to create it. The downside to this approach, no two projects are exactly the same, making it a little tricky on the initial estimate. For the sake of arriving to a base price model I have listed the basic production stages of most website projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research and Planning (3 hours +)
Design (14 hours)
Front-end development (11 hours)
Back-end development (5 hours)
Content entry with 4 sub pages (5 hours)
Site Testing (2 hours)
Go-live (2 hours)
Hours for a basic site = 42 hours
Project Management Time = additional 20% of total time (8.4)
TOTAL HOURS = 50.4
As you can see, a very basic website, 4–5 pages, takes at the minimum 50 hours to complete. This leads us to the question of value. How much is that web design &amp;amp; development hour worth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of factors can attribute to an hourly rate, but the wisdom grounded in getting what you pay for often holds the most weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A designer or agency of great quality and high demand is going to expect to be paid what they are worth. A freelance designer just starting out may tread lightly until he or she feels worthy of charging a more standard rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way you can expect to see hourly rates as low as $50 an hour to as high as $150 an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our above tally of a 50 hour site that translates to paying anywhere between:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$2520 to as high as $7560 for a basic website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do your research, ask good questions, and set your expectations in line with your budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you cut corners on price, rest assured that corners are being cut on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 11:23:16 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/web/design/marketing/2018/09/24/how-much-does-a-website-cost.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/web/design/marketing/2018/09/24/how-much-does-a-website-cost.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>5 Tips For Dads Working From Home</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I run up the stairs, I run down the stairs, I run up the stairs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really beginning to 2nd guess our decision to purchase this two story fixer-upper. At the very least I am heavily considering moving the baby’s room to the middle of the living room… perhaps to the middle of the garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my children. Fatherhood has forced a posture of servant-hood inescapable and void of choice. These two-story castle princesses give commands, I respond. Mostly in love, some days in fear (our baby is trying to kill me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working while serving these lovely ladies requires a lot of planning and a little bit of self-defense. I’ve come up with a list that helps me get all of us through the day, still alive and if all goes well, still loving one another…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Your 1st priority is yourself. If you are not OK, you are not going to be able to be the best you can be for your family or your work. Also, babies and toddlers sense weakness like blood hounds and will strike at the 1st sign of vulnerability. Make sure you are getting enough sleep at night. Give yourself time in the morning before everyone wakes for a little “me” time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Silence is NOT golden. If you cannot see your children, hmm… not the end of the world. If you cannot hear your children… CODE RED! Silence is bad and usually means $h!% has hit the fan. Literally… poop is currently being spread on the walls of the hallway. Gracefully mute your conference call and run as fast as you can towards the silence. Be sure not to slip in the $h!%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) Your children are people. Treat them as such. There is no substitution for spending time with your kids. While you obviously have projects and tasks and emails in need of your attention be sure to schedule time for playing. Even if it is just for 10 minutes at a time. Those moments will go a long way towards communicating to your children their value and will, with all hope, spare them the desire to pursue a career in reality TV. Dad’s, don’t raise reality TV stars!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) Feed your kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.) Have grace. The quickest path towards destruction is you losing your cool. So what? Your 3 year old just flipped out, knocked the phone out of your hand disconnecting the call with a client, while screaming what sounded like an obscenity, all because you whispered to her she could not have cake right now. You are not a failure. You are a parent. Remain calm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember she is just a kid and the withholding of cake is a very valid reason for anyone to flip out. You kind of had it coming.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 11:23:16 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/web/design/marketing/remote-work/2018/09/24/5-tips-for-dads-working-from-home.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/web/design/marketing/remote-work/2018/09/24/5-tips-for-dads-working-from-home.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to Get Your Website On Google</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn the Best Way to Get Your Website on the First Page of Google Search Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s coveted.  The pole position, the top dog, the cream of the crop – yes, getting to the first page of Google’s organic search results is the dream of most organizations using the web for business development.  No, it’s not impossible, and in this post, I’ll answer the question how to get your website on Google? I’ll discuss the four steps your organization needs to take in order to achieve the corner office of Google results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#1: Identify the Target Audience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting your website on page one of Google means you need to start with step 1 – identify your target audience.   Who is the ideal client you are going after? Once you’ve identified your target audience, you should take a look at your analytics to see if the people searching and going to your site fit with your target audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#2: Develop a Keyword Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the target audience has been identified, the step 2 of getting your website on Google is to develop a strategy around the keywords your target audience would use in their searches in order to find relevant information that your business is able to provide them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword strategy is an SEO term that is thrown around a lot, but in the most basic form, it involves getting into the minds of your users. If one of your potential customers is going to be looking for your products, how would they enter that in search? What key phrases and combinations of words might they use to find you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, if you’re trying to sell camera cases, your audience would search for things such as, “case” or “camera case.” You can use those high level ones, as well as longer keyword phrases. If your business is locally based, you can break it down by region, and add locations to your keyword phrases. For example, you may use a keyword phrase such as, “camera cases in Cleveland, Ohio.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#3 Create Valuable Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your keyword strategy is in place, it’s time to engage step 3 and create content. Getting your website on Google won’t happen without content. The content you create should tell a story or be relevant in some way to the keywords you’ve identified. You can do this in a number of ways, including everything from pushing out blog post to videos to providing content in the form of answers in frequently asked questions sections of your website.  Each of these elements needs to be relevant to your keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#4 Code to SEO Standards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have identified your keywords and created a content plan, it’s important to close the loop in step 4 and code your actual website so that it fits with SEO and usability standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if your goal was to sell camera cases, you would likely have a lot of images of camera cases on your site. Don’t just drop images with the default image titles such as Image001, Image002, etc., but instead, rename the images using relevant keywords. Camera-cases-for-on-the-go.jpeg is an example of a keyword rich image name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, it’s important to properly use H1 and H2 tags on your website. Google has gotten so good that it scans websites the same way a person would read a site. Because of this newer reality, it’s vital to design your code and content in a way that makes sense to your target users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While keywords are important, avoid stuffing too many keywords on your site. If you’re looking to get on the first page of Google, your site needs to be friendly and easy for your user to understand so that once they do get there, they’ll want to engage with your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it requires patience and commitment, my clients are able to achieve kingpin results by following the four steps described above.  Patience, persistence and an aggressive SEO/content strategy will ensure your organization achieves results in its organic search results. If you are still wondering “how to get my website on Google”, please contact me and I’ll be happy to discuss it in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 11:23:16 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/web/design/marketing/remote-work/seo/2018/07/24/how-to-get-your-website-on-google-search.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/web/design/marketing/remote-work/seo/2018/07/24/how-to-get-your-website-on-google-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
